<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-08-11T17:19:31-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Half-lifed.com</title><subtitle>Professional and personal development after turning 50.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Static sites and continous improvement</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/08/10/static-sites-and-continuous-improvement.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Static sites and continous improvement" /><published>2019-08-10T08:01:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-08-10T08:01:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/08/10/static-sites-and-continuous-improvement</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/08/10/static-sites-and-continuous-improvement.html">&lt;p&gt;Being 50, the web has intrigued me for decades. The tools have evolved and made things easier to build and deploy sites faster than ever. I’m not a developer, though. That’s a skillset that’s always eluded my time and commitment to become efficient and confident at coding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m what you’d call a classic “dabbler,” just dangerous enough to build, write content, and launch sites. Nothing to be proud of, but proud of trying, learning, and stretching my skills if possible. Learning the relationship between databases like MySQL and and PHP. This after building page after page after link after link to make a cohesive content experience for web “surfers.” PHP was my introduction to a rudimentary CMS (content management system). The sites became more functional in less time while content became easily created and changed if necessary. Wordpress became and thing and—WOW—here’s this team of 100s really pushing the envelope of what’s possible for content on a screen. Why reinvent the wheel every time, I thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruby on Rails was next. “Make a blog in less than 15 minutes.” I was hooked, so I dabbed a bit more. Again, not proud of anything. Just proud of pushing myself into new methods and various ways to manage and deploy content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Gzj723LkRJY&quot;&gt;Watch: Make a blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building websites for the masses is fun, but a website can be useful for smaller groups and even individuals. While my wife was coaching club volleyball, her biggest need from me was gathering stats. Paper stats are great but leave a lot to be desired for quick analysis. We needed an application for tracking the team, players, games, serves, passes, blocks, and kills. Ruby on Rails to the rescue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was the developer and end user. This scenario drove the largest collective chunk of learning about how the code works. The vision had to match the code. Form and function were aligned. The application is hideous looking. And beautiful at what it does — track volleyball game stats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At work, our current site &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.metergroup.com&quot;&gt;metergroup.com&lt;/a&gt; is built on Wordpress. We have a front end developer working on it, plus team members like myself adding content. Our next site is a radical departure from Wordpress. It’s going to be a static site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.half-lifed.com&quot;&gt;half-lifed.com&lt;/a&gt;, is the work of learning Jekyll, a static site tool. It’s a bit confusing so far, but that’s because I’m learning yet another new method. But, it’s like we’ve come full circle in a way. Every page intentioned. Every image purposed. Static sites are generated quickly from tools like Jekyll, and a myriad of other solutions. However, the work resembles the work of old where pages are rolled out one at a time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Being 50, the web has intrigued me for decades. The tools have evolved and made things easier to build and deploy sites faster than ever. I’m not a developer, though. That’s a skillset that’s always eluded my time and commitment to become efficient and confident at coding.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How this started</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/08/07/welcome.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How this started" /><published>2019-08-07T21:24:03-07:00</published><updated>2019-08-07T21:24:03-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/08/07/welcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/08/07/welcome.html">&lt;p&gt;Catching inspiration by the tail is nearly impossible. Inspiration grabs us by the neck whenever it wants, randomly, and unexpectedly.
Inspiration’s elixir is, well, anything. Half-lifed is the culmination of a lot of thinking, sorting out what it means to be 50, your life half lived, finding yourself and being comfortable with where self is found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Done a lot of thinking, doing a lot of thinking. The thinking part never ends. Never. Eventually the doing has to happen. In other words, the inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;goals-of-this-blog&quot;&gt;Goals of this blog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Personal development&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Professional development&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stories about people who practice both&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Catching inspiration by the tail is nearly impossible. Inspiration grabs us by the neck whenever it wants, randomly, and unexpectedly. Inspiration’s elixir is, well, anything. Half-lifed is the culmination of a lot of thinking, sorting out what it means to be 50, your life half lived, finding yourself and being comfortable with where self is found.</summary></entry></feed>